If you don't know how to use a computer, we will teach you here.
如果你不会用电脑 我们可以教你
Most jobs require at least basic word processing skills.
大多数工作都需要你至少会用文字处理软件的
We try to get you up to 50 words per minute.
我们会尽量让你的打字速度达到50字每分钟
We also have a course in how to talk to someone in an interview.
我们还有专门的课程 辅导你在面试中怎么表达自己
Stuff like what employers are looking for,
比如说招聘方寻找的是什么样的人啊
how to turn negatives into positives.
如何将自己的劣势转化为优势啊等等
We can also provide clothes for the interview if you need them.
我们还可以提供适合面试时穿的服装
People donate shoes and suits all the time.
很多人向我们捐献西装和皮鞋的
Wh-what if I had a history with, uh...
那如果我...
With drugs? That is nothing to be ashamed of.
- 曾经吸毒怎么办? - 这个也没关系的
Many of our clients have struggled with addiction,
很多我们的顾客都有药瘾方面的问题
and, if you want to get clean, we'll help you do that.
如果你想要戒瘾的话呢 我们也可以帮你实现的
And what if I have a kid?
如果我还有孩子怎么办?
No one to help you?
没人帮你照看吗?
You know, if I need someone to watch her while I'm in class or, uh, on an interview.
我是说 如果我在上课 或者面试的时候需要人照顾她的话...
Could you help with that? We do not provide child care.
- 你们能帮助我吗? - 我们不提供托儿服务
Actually, it's something that comes up often.
而且这个问题其实挺经常出现的
I would love to be able to do it. I just don't have the resources.
我其实挺想在这方面做点什么 实在是没这个能力
But it's definitely on the wish list.
但这绝对是我们希望能够实现的
Okay.
好的
Okay, uh, thank you.
谢谢你了
I'll be back. Oh, I have to take this.
- 我会再来的 - 抱歉 我得接一下电话
Yes, please come back, and we'll get you started.
请一定再来啊 我们会帮你重新开始的
It was nice to meet you, Benjamin. Okay.
- 很高兴认识你 Benjamin - 嗯
Hey, Oscar.
你好 Oscar
Agh! Oh, that is too bad.
啊! 真是糟糕
Did they tell you why?
他们告诉你为什么了吗?
Yeah.
好吧
Well, you know what? Sometimes, you just don't get the job, but...
你知道吗? 有时找工作确实会遇到困难 但是...
Oscar, I gotta call you back.
Oscar 我再打给你
REMITTER BENJAMIN BYRD FOUNDATION/PAY TO THE PHOENIC FOUNDATION / ONE MILLION DOALLRS
100万美金 收款方:凤凰城基金会
Benjamin! Benjamin, wait!
Benjamin! Benjamin 等等!
Oh, my God. Uh...
天哪...
Somebody call an ambulance!
快叫救护车!
-==破烂熊乐园倾情奉献==- 本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业用途
-==破烂熊乐园倾情奉献==- 本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业用途
-=破烂熊字幕组=- 翻译：ID 校对：ID 时间轴：爱米胖依然如昔
-==http://www.ragbear.com==- 豪斯医生 第8季第3集
-==http://www.ragbear.com==- 豪斯医生 第8季第3集
-=破烂熊字幕组=- 翻译：fflonestar 英伦 校对：理智的李主任新婚快乐 生活甜蜜蜜哟 时间轴：爱米胖依然如昔
* Gotta build *
* Gotta build *
* and destroy *
* and destroy *
* then rebuild *
* then rebuild *
* oh, I'm gonna build, build, build *
* oh, I'm gonna build, build, build *
* destroy *
* destroy *
* then rebuild *
* then rebuild *
* and destroy *
* and destroy *
Why am I watching you cut your hair?
我为什么要站这儿看你剪头发?
If I do it at home, I'm the one who has to clean it up.
如果我在家剪 最终还得自己收拾
Does a friend watch you where it's happening, and wonder why?
那是常有朋友站在一旁参观 纳闷这是为何吗?
New life, new look.
新生活 新形象嘛
Does that mean you like your new life?
这是不是说你喜欢你的新生活了?
If you're asking if your job is safe,
如果你想知道你这份工作是不是保得住
that depends on what you have to say about the file you're holding.
那跟你对手里拿的病历 怎么说有直接关系
It doesn't seem like much of a case.
不像是个有劲的病例
Although, I'm sure I'm wrong.
不过 我肯定我说得不对
You are. Tell my why.
你是不对 告诉我为什么
Guy collapsed after being on his feet for hours on a hot day without breakfast...
一个男的在大热天不吃早饭 然后在大太阳底下站了几个小时 结果昏倒了
So that's really weird. E.R. found nothing wrong.
- 这挺奇怪的吧 - ER没发现任何问题
Then I decided I should test his wallet.
然后我决定检查一下他的钱包
He's rich? That's why we're taking the case?
他很有钱? 我们就为这接了他?
No, we're taking the case because no one knows what's wrong with him.
不 我们接了他是因为没人知道他到底怎么了
And he's rich.
而且他也有钱
Dr. Adams.
Adams医生
Give her the file.
把病历给她
This is my only copy.
我只有这一份
My M.O. depends upon the use of a team.
我的工作方式依靠于一个小组的存在
Definitionally, that involves... more than one person.
从定义上来说 小组代表着两人及以上
So I really have no choice. Give her the file.
所以我没别的选择 把病历给她
You can't afford a team. Adams is free.
- 你请不起小组 - Adams不要钱 (有空)
And I'm referring both to her availability and her price tag.
我说的既是她的价钱 也是她目前的生活状态哟
New girl, meet newer girl, and vice versa.
新来的妞 来见见更新的妞 然后反之亦然一下
You said we were meeting for coffee.
你是让我来喝咖啡的
Well, when someone asks if you want coffee,
如果有人问你要不要喝咖啡
they obviously don't just mean coffee.
显然是醉翁之意不在咖啡啊
Wait...did you think I was referring to sex?
等下...你以为我说的是搞?
Would you shut the blinds on your way out?
你出去的时候把门帘子拉上行不?
I thought you were referring to talking. Talking about medicine.
- 我以为你是想和我谈谈 - 无非就是谈医学上的事情
Specifically, as it refers to the guy
具体点说 也就是这个病人
whose name is on the file she still hasn't handed you.
他的名字写在小蘑菇头仍旧不肯给你的那份病历上
I'm not working, House. I'm in the process of looking for a paying job.
我现在没空 House 我正在找一份有薪水的工作
In the meantime, there's no way a do-gooder like you has been volunteering
同时 你这种好心人是绝无可能
all over town-- ladling kittens, spaying soup...
满城乱转替人抱抱小猫啊 送送爱心汤啊什么的...
There is a free clinic in Trenton.
特伦顿是有家免费诊所
Well, think of this as today's free clinic.
好啊 那就把这个当今天的免费诊所吧
Only with fewer bums with herpes.
只不过少了很多得了脏病的流浪汉而已
I don't think we actually have much of a case. I think it's just
我本来就不觉得这是个什么特别的病历
What happened the last time another doctor told you I was wrong about a case?
上回有医生告诉你我错了的时候发生什么了
I lost my job. You saved a life.
- 我被炒了鱿鱼 - 你救了一条人命
Is an ultrasound really necessary? I'm feeling much better now.
真的有必要做超声检查吗? 我觉得已经好多了啊
Oh, a sudden collapse at your age can indicate a deterioration of the heart muscle.
你这个年纪忽然昏倒可能说明你的心脏肌肉正在退化
Pretty serious condition.
挺严重的病呢
It can also just be dehydration.
或者也可能只是脱水而已
Next time, you could probably drop the undercover act.
下次你就别去做卧底了嘛
I walk in in a suit,
如果我穿着身西装走进去
and they're gonna put their best foot forward.
他们肯定会拼命讨好我
Also, I don't own a suit.
并且 我也没有西装
You give away millions and you don't own a suit?
你几百万几百万往外捐钱 但自己连套西服都没有?
I gave those away too.
那些我也捐了
One day, I was writing a check to my landscaper, and it suddenly hit me--
有一天我正在给我的景观设计师开支票 然后忽然意识到--
$6,000 to take out plants and put in different plants.
六千块钱 就是把现在种的花花草草拔掉 再种上新的花花草草
So I can look at them.
好让我看着舒心
Shouldn't I use that money to do something important?
我就不能用这钱去做些更重要的事情吗?
And by money, you mean all your money.
你的意思是用你所有的钱吧
I started with 10 million,
我先捐了一千万
and I couldn't think of a reason not to give 20.
然后又觉得 我没理由不再捐两千万啊
Or 40.
或者四千万
I figure I could live off $25,000 a year.
我估摸着我一年用两万五也就够了
One-room apartment. Bus pass, thrift stores.
就租一间房 出门用公交卡 东西在二手店买
Bare necessities.
只满足基本需要就行了
I still have my software company.
但我还是拥有我的软件公司
And when I make more, I'll give that way too.
等我赚了更多的钱 我就把那些也捐掉
- He's nuts. - He's generous.
- 他是个傻子 - 他是个乐善好施的人
There's a neurological issue. He's getting rid of everything.
这显然是神经有问题 他啥都不要了
His echocardiogram is negative for cardiomyopathy.
他的超声波心电图并未显示心肌炎
Head CT showed no signs of stroke or hemorrhage. He has one pair of pants.
- 头部CT没有任何中风或出血的迹象 - 他只有一条裤子!
Most people with his kind of money are commissioning oil paintings of their Yorkshire terrier.
大多数像他这么有钱的人 早开始请画师给自家的狗狗画油画了
Benjamin is sacrificing his own comfort to help others.
Benjamin为助人牺牲了自己的安逸
That's because helping others is his Yorkie oil painting.
那是因为助人对他来说和给狗画像是一个意思
That's good. Not sick.
这是好事啊 不是病
That's naive and sick. You really want to improve things?
这是很傻很有病 你真想拯救世界啊?
You do it through policy.
那要从政策上下手好么
This guy empties his pockets, what really changes?
就算这人把口袋掏个底朝天 能改变什么?
That's right, all those babies with aids, they're just using us.
没错 那些生来就有艾滋病的孩子 都是利用我们呢
My parents had $800 between them when they got here.
我爸妈来到美国的时候口袋里只有800块钱
They scraped and borrowed so we could go to good schools,
他们省吃俭用 四处举债 好让我能上一流的学校
and I worked my ass off.
我自己也是拼了命
No one gave me a handout. It makes me work harder.
没人平白无故地施舍我 但这让我更加倍努力
Rebuttal.
反方发言
What's your evil plan? I object to your cynicism.
- 你又有什么邪恶的计划了? - 我讨厌你的愤世嫉俗
- It's been earned. - That's what I object to.
- 多年习惯 - 这个我也讨厌
The new Dean of Medicine has an ethical obligation
新的院长有义务
to come in with a completely open mind about all employees,
以开放的心态接受任何新的雇员
thus letting me blithely run roughshod for at least four weeks.
于是你应该允许我快乐地横行霸道至少四周
My theory is that you're running a battery of tests
我的理论是你现在乱做测试
to convince him that you saved his life, then con him into funding you to hire back your team.
是为了骗他相信你救了他的命 然后再骗他给你掏钱 好让你收复失地
- What? - Your old team?
- 啥? - 你以前的手下?
What? This is your new reality.
- 啥啊? - 你要看清眼下的事实
You've got your office. You've got neighbors.
你有这间办公室 有邻居
You've got one employee, one volunteer.
一个雇员 以及一个志愿帮忙的
Until she finds actual, paid work, or gets sick of you.
直到她找到正式的有偿工作 或者彻底受够你
I talked to Chase and Taub. They're willing to come back.
我跟Chase和Taub谈过了 他们都想回来
What about Thirteen? Not a good choice.
- 那13呢? - 她可不是个好选择
She's not long term because she has no long term.
她没法长期工作是因为她已经没长期可言了
Not taking your calls?
她不接你电话?
She will.
她会接的
Discharge the patient.
让病人出院
Unexplained loss of consciousness could be cardiomyopathy,
无法解释的忽然失去知觉可能是心肌炎
global anoxia, subarachnoid hemorrhage--
全身性缺氧 蛛网膜下腔出血--
dehydration. He was given fluids, and he got better.
或者脱水 他补充液体之后就好多了
And I'm sure your tests have come up negative, or you would have shut me up already.
我确定你的测试结果已经否定这些了 要不你早就让我闭嘴了
Which means he goes home.
这就是说 该让他出院了
There is a symptom...
还有个症状
Extreme altruism.
极端利他主义
You've got two choices, House.
House 现在有两个选择
You can recognize that your patient is just a very nice, healthy guy,
要么意识到你的病人只是一个乐善好施的健康人
and send him home, or you can consider altruism a symptom.
然后送他回家 要么你把极端利己主义列入症状
In which case, you cannot take his money.
如果这样的话呢 你就不能拿他的钱了
Send him home. And check with admitting
打发他走 然后去接诊处探听一下
for the net worth of all new patients.
所有新病人的总身价有多少
I'm not coming back, House.
我不会再回来了 House
Technically, you're back right now.
实际上 你现在就已经回来了
I need you to stop calling me. First 17 messages were cute, but--
拜托你别再给我打电话了 前17通留言还挺可爱的 但是...
I'm putting the band back together.
我要重新把大家召集到一块儿了
Interesting that you never showed up at my place, what with your love of annoying me
你从来没跑来我家烦我 这对于你一贯热爱惹人讨厌
and your inability to take no for an answer.
并且不接受拒绝的特质来说真是个奇迹
I'm guessing ankle monitor.
想必脚上被装了监控吧
Guilty as charged.
我认罪伏法
Literally.
真是伏法了哦
I'm not a doctor anymore, House.
我已经不当医生了 House
The job went away, but not the profession.
工作没有了 但你的专业知识还在
You look healthy, so... That's not it.
你看起来活蹦乱跳 所以...身体不是原因
You met a boy. Or a girl.
你遇到了一个男孩 或者一个女孩
Fall in love, wanna be happy.
坠入了爱河 想要幸福起来
You decided to... Enjoy what time you have left.
你决定要...享受你剩下的时光
You're going to Thailand.
你要到泰国去了
Girl.
是女孩
And Mykonos.
而且是米科诺斯岛 (希腊爱琴海上的小岛)
Turns out I like boring.
我发现我其实是喜欢无聊的
No, you wanna like boring.
不 你想要喜欢无聊
But if you actually liked boring, you would have figured that out in fifth grade,
如果你真的喜欢无聊 你五年级无聊的时候
when you were bored. Please stop calling me.
- 你早就悟出来了 - 拜托别再打给我了 好么
No.
不好
You showed up to tell me that you don't want to hear from me.
你跑来就是想告诉我 不想跟我扯上关系
That's a mixed signal.
这是典型的混合信号
I will choose to listen to your actions rather than your words.
我选择相信你的行动而非你的话语
They're more honest.
因为行动总是更诚实的
I'm a little confused.
我有点不明白
The test is designed to determine if you're--
这个测试是为了检查你是不是--
No, I mean your running a test and discharging me.
不 我是说你怎么又做测试又让我出院的
Was I dehydrated or not? I think so.
- 我到底是不是脱水了? - 我认为是的
But, out of an abundance of caution,
不过 因为瞎操心
my colleague has taken it upon herself to do one more test.
我的同事想要再多做一个测试.
All right.
好的
You scare me a little.
你有点可怕哟
Why?
为什么?
I've been considering applying to Doctors Without Borders.
我想过申请加入医生无国界组织
Going overseas a while, and that seems like a huge sacrifice.
去海外呆个几年 可又觉得那样个人牺牲太大了
But...You-- you don't scare her.
- 但是你... - 你才不是让她害怕呢
You make her feel guilty.
你只是让她觉得有负罪感
Oh, you...
哦 你...
You like your life that way it is. Most people give the minimum they have to give
你喜欢现在的生活 大多数人都只是作出最微薄的贡献
so they can enjoy what they have left. I guess my minimum is just...
从而享受剩下的一切 我想我最微薄的贡献
Higher than most. Complete recruitment and interference pattern.
- 只是比别人多而已 - 循环及扰动模式完整
His leg muscles are fine.
他的腿部肌肉没事
I feel, uh, funny.
我觉得不舒服
Where? My chest.
- 哪不舒服? - 胸口
You're tachycardic. Your heart's beating too fast.
你心动过速了
Unbelievable.
不可能啊
Patient got tachycardic to 185.
病人心动过速 心跳达到185
We pushed 18 milligrams adenosine.
我们推注了18毫克的腺苷
There's definitely something wrong with him. Which is awesome.
- 他的确有问题 - 那可好极啦
Now there's something to cure,
有病可治了
which means there's something to be disproportionately financially grateful for.
也就是说有大笔的轻松银子可赚了
Morning. Got you a coffee.
早上好啊 给你买了咖啡
Thanks.
谢了
Arrhythmia could easily have caused the collapse
发病的原因可能只是简单的心率不齐
that landed Father Teresa in here in the first place.
也就是特蕾莎修男进来的原因
Oh, that's fine. Keep it.
哦 没关系的 我请你
We looked at his heart yesterday, didn't see any structural abnormalities.
我们昨天检查过他的心脏 我并没有发现任何结构性病变
I'm thinking occult long QT syndrome?
我在想是突发性长QT波症吗?
What about Whipple's? If it was Whipple's, there'd be some kind of neurological involvement.
- 那惠普尔症呢?(肠源性脂肪代谢障碍症) - 如果是惠普尔 那么应该有神经方面的症状
You don't think defying human nature is neurological?
你不觉得和人性背道而驰是神经症状吗?
Racing heart: Medical condition. Bleeding heart: Stupid condition.
心动过速: 医学症状 大爱无疆: 蠢货一个
Are you saying that because you believe it, or because it's in your financial best interest
你这么说是因为你相信这个呢 还是因为从财政上考虑
to think his generosity isn't just temporary?
你希望他的慷慨不只是暂时的?
I'm told that some people are just nice.
有人告诉我这世界上就是有好人呢
I'm trying to embrace that wisdom.
我不是正在试着接近真理么
Benjamin's been taking allergy medication the last few weeks.
Benjamin这几个星期一直在服抗过敏药物
Long QT syndrome can be medication-induced.
长QT波症可能被药物所引发
Flush him with saline, get rid of the antihistamines,
给他大量输入盐水 让抗组织胺酶代谢出他的身体
then do an EKG.
然后做个心电图
No, wait. I'll do the flushing.
不 等一下 我来给他输液
Take the damn $2.00. She hasn't even sipped the coffee.
你就赶紧接了那两块钱吧 那咖啡人家还一口没喝呢
I just got so angry. You know?
我当时好气愤哦 你知道么?
So I made a terrible mistake.
于是就犯了个好大的错误
Now I'm trying to start my life over.
现在我想要重新开始呢
To help people the way I always wanted.
以我一直希望的方式去帮助人们
But my department got defunded, and...
但是我部门的资金被抽掉了...
it's my fault.
都是我的错
Just can't stand to think of all those patients
一想那些病人可能会
going untreated because I don't have the resources to do my best work.
因为我缺少资源而没人救治 我这心里就难受啊
How about I help you out? How do you mean?
- 我帮帮你怎么样? - 你是什么意思呢?
I'll give $1 million as an endowment to the hospital,
我会给你们医院捐一百万
earmarked for diagnostics.
专门注明给诊断科
I am an opportunistic ex-con
我是一个机会主义的前科犯
who just gave you a two-minute sob story
编了一个两分钟的心碎小故事给你听
as step three in my master plan,
这还是我宏伟计划的第三步而已
and you've offered me $1 million.
你这就乖乖掏了一百万?
Which is step 17.
我以为要到第十七步才能引你中招呢
Is that bad?
这不好吗?
Ethics are not my strong suit.
道德可不是我的强项
Hypothetical-- if I'm offered oral sex
假设: 有个性瘾者主动提出
from a sexaholic, do I have to decline?
要给我吹箫 我是不是非得拒绝呢?
Don't answer yet.
先别回答哦
Saying no will cause both of us pain.
说不 我们俩就都苦逼了
Saying yes will cause both of us pleasure.
而说是 我们俩就都极乐了
You can't take sex from a sexaholic.
你不能跟性瘾者发生性关系
You can't give booze to an alcoholic, and you can't take this guy's money.
也不能给酒鬼酒喝 同样也不能拿你病人的钱
Could be wrong about the symptom. I'm wrong all the time.
说不定我症状找错了呢 我反正老错的嘛
Taking money from a sick person is ethically suspect at best.
从病人手里拿钱 最乐观的结果 也是被人质疑职业道德
What is this, Canada?
你以为这是哪儿啊 加拿大吗?
All we do is take money from sick people. We work for it.
- 我们整天不就是从病人手里拿钱呢! - 那是我们工作所得
I'm working! How much?
- 我工作了呀! - 你拿多少钱?
$20. Well, what if it was?
...一小时20块... 是又怎样啊
It's the same principle. $20, $1 million... What's the difference?
这大道理不是一样的吗 20块 一百万 有啥区别?
Actually, the difference is pretty much $1 million.
这区别说起来要差不多一百万呢
He came up with the figure, not me.
数字是他提的 又不是我
Crap.
该死
Got a patient with end stage renal disease.
有个肾病晚期的病人
Her heart can't support dialysis.
她的心脏承受不了透析了
She needs a transplant, but...
她需要肾移植 但是...
you tuned out as soon as it stopped being about you, didn't you?
一不说你的事了你立刻就神游了是吧?
- What? - I gotta go.
- 啥? - 我得走了
It's all moot.
都是扯淡
Patient probably has long QT.
说不定病人有长QT波症
Probably just a really, really decent person.
或者可能只是个特别特别好的人罢了
They exist, right? You can't take the money, House.
- 这种人是存在的 是吧? - 不准拿人家的钱 House
Is long QT bad?
这个长QT波症是坏事吗?
It's a tough thing to control.
要控制不太容易
Is there someone you want me to call?
你需要我给谁打电话不?
There's someone I would like to call.
确实有个人
She's the same person who won't take my calls.
而她也是唯一一个不肯接我电话的人
My wife.
我妻子
When I started giving away the money, I--
当我开始把钱都捐出去的时候 我--
I hoped she'd want to do it with me. She didn't.
我希望她能支持我 但她没有
I miss them.
我很想他们
I have two little boys.
我有两个小儿子
Having a family doesn't exempt me from social responsibility.
但家庭并不能免除我的社会责任
But family comes first.
但是家庭总是第一位的啊
It should.
并不应该是这样
I know that sounds weird, but... someone who's related to you,
我知道这样说很奇怪 但是... 为什么和你有血缘关系的人
does that empirically make them more special? More deserving than anyone else?
通常就被视为更特别 比他人更值得照顾呢?
Yes, it gives you a responsibility.
是啊 因为家庭给了你责任
My boys have a roof over their heads.
我的孩子们有容身之地
They're not starving.
有食物可以果腹
I pay court-ordered child support,
我也定时送上法庭规定的抚养费
and, frankly, it's, uh... more than they need.
并且 说实话 给的比他们需要的还要多
I love them more than anything, I just...
我非常非常爱他们 只是...
I can't justify buying video games and private schools
在其他孩子挨饿的时候 我不能放任自己给他们买电玩
when other people's children are starving.
送他们去贵族学校
I hope, one day, they'll understand that.
我希望有一天他们能够明白我的苦心
Your hands are trembling. Is it the electrodes?
- 你的手在抖 - 是电流的关系吗?
Are you in pain? No.
- 你觉得哪里疼吗? - 没有啊
What's happening? I'm not sure, but it's not what we thought it was.
- 怎么了? - 我不知道 但肯定不是我们想的那样
So...
那么...
arrhythmia, fainting, muscle tremors. Plus, unfortunately, mental changes.
心律不齐 休克 肌肉颤抖 加上 很不幸 精神变化
I still don't think it's neurological.
我依然觉得这不是神经症状
God bless you.
上帝保佑你
He lost his wife and kids because she couldn't stop giving money away.
他因为不停捐钱连老婆孩子都不要他了
He lost his wife because she couldn't accept not being filthy rich.
他的老婆离开他是因为 她不能接受他不愿当一个肮脏的富人这一事实
She's not drinking the coffee either. Drink it, don't drink it.
- 她也没喝你给她的咖啡哟 - 喝不喝我不管
The point is, I gave it to you, so we're even.
反正我已经替她买了 我们俩扯平了
Even? It was a gift.
扯平了? 一点小心意而已
An insignificant token. There was nothing owed.
就一杯咖啡 至于讲什么欠不欠吗?
That was the whole point. Why?
- 这样就完了啊 - 为啥?
Yeah, why?
- 什么为啥啊? - 对哦 为啥为啥啊?
She's the crazy one.
她才脑筋不正常好吗
So a guy gives everything Sane.
那么说一个把所有东西都捐给陌生人的人是正常的
Girl who doesn't want anything from a stranger is crazy.
另一个不拿陌生人东西的人就脑筋不正常了?
You're not a stranger.
可你不是陌生人呀
And your perverse view of the world is making you force a neurological component
并且你扭曲的世界观已经让你把神经症状
onto an obviously cardiological-- Your parents didn't love you enough.
- 强加于显而易见的心脏问题之上... - 你爸妈爱你不够
So you need to prove your superiority.
于是你就老想证明高人一等
Or they love you too much, so you need to prove your humility.
或者他们太过溺爱你了 于是你老想证明自己的谦虚恭谨
Or it's just rich guilt.
或者也许就是有钱人的负罪感呢
I'm betting on the last one.
我觉得肯定是最后一条
There's a whole list of drugs that could have caused his symptoms.
有很多药物可能导致他的症状
I doubt the guy would spend money on drugs
我才不相信有的孤儿还看不上有线电视
when there are orphans out there without cable.
这人会花钱买非法药物呢
Anyway, he'd be getting better right now, not worse.
不管怎么说 他应该好转而不是恶化了
Could be polyarteritis nodosa. That comes with a rash.
- 可能是结节性多动脉炎 - 那样的话他会起疹子的
Echovirus.
埃可病毒
Virus, virus, virus, virus... Fits his physical symptoms.
- 病毒 毒 毒 毒... - 和他的身体症状符合
And could,
并且可能
but doesn't necessarily cause personality changes.
但并非一定会造成性格改变
Works for everyone?
大家都同意吗?
Start him on antivirals.
给他上抗生素
And, Adams... when you treat,
Adams 当你给他治疗
and he gets better,
他好了之后
and doesn't give Bob Cratchit Christmas day off, you owe me a coffee.
变成吝啬凶狠的富人了的话 你欠我一杯咖啡哟 (Bob Cratchit是里的人物)
Click the third tab from the left
点从左数第三个标签
and find the box that says "previous entries."
找到写着"过往病历"的那一栏
You get a drop-down menu sorted by patient name and department.
然后会有下拉菜单显示病人的名字和收治科室
Thank you. Appreciate your help.
谢谢你帮忙咯
You're gonna read too much into this, aren't you? No, not at all.
- 你又要自作多情胡思乱想了是么? - 哪有的事
We're gonna fundamentally disagree about what it means to read too much into this.
我们对"自作多情胡思乱想"的定义 有着根本的分歧
Aren't we? Yes, absolutely.
- 不是么? - 绝对是
Look, I thought about what you said, and I realized you were right.
我想了想你跟我说的话 然后意识到你是对的
Great. See you tomorrow morning.
好极啦 明早见
No, you won't. Afternoon?
- 不 明早见不了 - 那下午?
I can't think of another interpretation.
我可再想不出另一种弦外之音啦
Shut up.
闭嘴
Look, I'm not sure what you were trying to achieve.
我不确定你想达到什么目的
I'm never quite sure.
我反正一直都不确定
But you were actually a friend to me when I needed it.
但是在我最需要的时候哥们你挺够义气的
I don't wanna come back to work for you.
我不想再回去给你工作了
But I was wrong to try to push you out of my life.
但是把你完全赶出我的生活呢是我不对
Everything has gone blue.
所有东西都变成蓝色的了耶
That's not supposed to happen, right?
这有点不对吧
Stay there. I'm comin'. No...You don't have to do that.
- 等着 我就来了 - 矮油 你可不用这样呀
Although, if you did come, maybe you could swing by the Hunan Palace
不过 如果你真来的话 能不能替我去川湘宫
and get some lo mein and a szechuan beef.
买碗拉面以及一份香辣牛肉?
That is six miles out of my way. Oh, okay, then.
- 那样的话我要绕六里地呢 - 哦 那算了
Guess I'll get something from the hospital cafeteria,
我随便在楼下自助餐厅买点算了
which is where I get all my meals since I can't go anywhere.
反正我哪也去不了 所以餐餐都在那儿吃的
Fine. I'll get the food.
好 我给你买吃的还不成吗
You're a peach.
你真是个小可爱
I started the last round of pleconaril.
我进行了最后一轮的Pleconaril(抗病毒药物)
Can you do me a favor?
帮我个忙行吗?
A favor?
帮忙?
You want me to return these? Give them to someone?
你想让我帮你退了? 给别人?
Wear them while you masturbate?
在你自摸的时候穿上这个?
I...want you to have them.
我想送给你
That's not a favor.
这可不是帮忙
It was a two-for-one sale. I couldn't resist. I need to justify buying them.
买一送一我克制不住 我需要给自己找个理由
They're $120.
价值120块
My car is in the shop. I'm short on cash this month.
我的车还在店里 这个月手头紧
I can't pay you back.
我没法给你钱
The first pair were $120.
第一双是120
These...were free.
这双免费
You do know I punched the last person that pissed me off?
你应该知道我打了上一个惹我的人吧?
Was it Santa?
圣诞老人吗?
What's your patient's status?
病人状况如何?
Better. We're discharging him.
好多了 他可以出院了
Good.
好极了
Why do you care?
你怎么那么关心?
Specifically.
具体地说
Although I'm curious about a general answer too.
不过我对笼统答案也挺好奇的
Your guy just signed up to donate a kidney to my patient with renal failure.
那人刚签字同意捐肾给我肾衰竭的病人
Did he meet your patient with renal failure?
他见过你那个肾衰竭的病人?
No, he heard the nurses talking about her, that she was short on time.
没 他听见了护士的谈话 说她快没有时间了
I was wrong. Don't say that.
- 我错了 - 别这么说
House, she really needs this kidney.
House 她真的需要肾移植
He's not better. His mental status is declining.
他还没好 精神状态在衰退
Or he's doing an amazing thing for another human being.
或者他是在为另一个人做一件了不起的好事
I thought it was an ethical no-brainer that we can't take stuff from sick people.
这是伦理性的常识吧 不能拿病人的东西
I changed my mind.
我改变主意了
He's still sick. His symptoms have gone away.
- 他还病着 - 症状已经消失了
Not all of them.
并非全部
Offering an organ to a stranger is a symptom.
想为陌生人捐赠器官就是症状
A couple dozen people a year make undirected kidney donations.
一年有几十个人无指定地捐赠肾脏
Yeah, how many of them are also in the process of pauperizing themselves?
那有多少也在让自己越过越穷?
If the guy threw himself on a grenade, he'd be a hero.
如果这人主动赌枪眼 那他就是英雄
If it saves a life, who cares? You do!
- 如果能救人一命 谁在乎? - 你在乎!
Yesterday, when you made the exact opposite argument.
昨天你还在持反对意见
If there's even a chance I'm right,
只要有可能我是对的
it'd be dangerous to give his kidney to someone else.
把他的肾移植给别人就会有危险
More dangerous than complete renal failure? My patient needs this.
比完全肾衰竭更危险? 我的病人真的很需要
Now. Why do you wanna give away your kidney?
- 现在就要 - 你为什么要捐肾?
There are 70,000 people in this country
这个国家有7万人等着接受肾移植
If only we could kill 60,000 more people a year, all would be golden.
要是能每年多弄死6万人 就万事大吉了
I'll give you your money.
我会把钱给你的
See? Crazy.
看见没? 疯了
Being a live donor has risks. I looked it up.
- 活体捐赠有风险 - 我查过了
The risk is 1 in 4,000 I could die during surgery,
手术中死亡率是4千分之一
which means, if I don't donate,
也就是说 如果我不捐
I'm valuing my life at 4,000 times someone else's.
就表示我把自己的生命看得比别人重要4千倍
It's not like I want to be cut open and have a part of me taken out.
我也不想被人割开 取走身体一部分
But I've got two, and this woman has none.
可我有两个肾 那个女人却一个也没有
She'll die without it. Perfectly logical.
- 不给她会死 - 很有逻辑
People with mental deficiency can be logical.
智力障碍的人也能很有逻辑的啊
that he's sick.
正如同心智健全的人 也会没有逻辑一样
??????????
这个肾 是你唯一可以证明他有病的证据
I'm gonna let him be a donor.
我同意他捐赠
Dr. House, it's not a symptom.
House医生 这不是症状
Come back after you're convinced that I'm healthy, and I will give you your money.
等你相信我很健康之后再来吧 我会把钱给你的
No, you won't.
不 你不会
We have time for one more test before we move him.
在把他转移之前 我们还有时间再做个测试
What test? Whatever test will prove
- 什么测试 - 只要能证明
there was an echovirus-irus-irus, and he's not cured, obviously.
存在埃可病毒毒毒 他并未被治愈
I've been saying all along this could be Whipple's.
我一直都说这可能是Whipples尔病
Causes arrhythmia, tremor, and mental changes.
导致心律不齐 战栗 心理变化
Bad idea. There's no joint pain.
不对 没有关节疼痛
Where's Adams? We thought the case was over.
- Adams在哪? - 我们还以为诊断结束了
She has a job interview.
她去工作面试了
Why is she here?
她怎么在这里?
'Cause I called her.
我给她打了电话
Bigger question is why that worked. I'm here because I have time
- 更大的疑问是 怎么一叫就到 - 因为我有时间
and you have a crisis and I-- we're too busy for rationalizations.
- 而你有麻烦 我 - 没时间解释了
Patient made a big downgrade in his personal life.
病人让自己的生活水平大幅度下降
He's probably not eating all that healthy. Magnesium deficiency?
- 很可能他吃得不太健康 - 缺镁元素?
Wait until they take him back to his room--draw blood,
等他被带回房间 给他抽血
do an expanded electrolyte profile.
做个详尽的血生化
No, he hasn't had anxiety or any trouble sleeping.
不对 他并无焦虑 睡眠也没问题
I think it's Whipple's disease. Bad idea. He doesn't have joint pain.
- 我觉得是惠普尔病 - 错 他没感到关节疼痛
Joint pain is common, but not definitive.
关节疼痛很普遍 但并非绝对
Whipple's explains all of his symptoms,
惠普尔病能解释他所有症状
including the personality change.
包括性格转变
And it would respond to antibiotics, which is why he started to feel better.
而且对抗生素有反应 所以他有所好转
Which doesn't mean he's not still sick. You were right.
- 这不代表他没病了 - 你是对的
Counts for nothing if you can't defend it.
无法辩护你的论点也就毫无价值
Book a procedure room.
预约个手术室
Do an upper endoscopy and run a PCR test for Whipple's.
做个上内视镜 再来个PCR检测 看是否为惠普尔病
Guilt.
内疚
You feel guilty about leaving.
你为自己的离开感到内疚
Yes, I think that little of you and that much of me.
是的 我把你想得太渺小 把自己想得太伟大
You're nothing without me. Not leaving me.
- 没有我你什么都不是 - 不是离开我
Leaving humanity.
是丢下人性
I'm going with my girlfriend.
我要和我女朋友一起
The woman I love. To have fun.
- 我爱她 - 去享乐
You're trying to make me feel guilty because you're saving lives here.
你想让我感到内疚 因为你在这里拯救生命
And I think that's great. I'm proud to have been a part of it,
我觉得这是好事 我为自己曾是其中一员而感到自豪
but...now...
只是... 现在...
I just wanna be happy.
我想过得开心
Oh...no one's unhappy in Greece.
哦 在希腊人人都开心
It just appeared in the last few weeks.
上几周才出现的
He's having trouble holding a pencil in school. Does it itch?
- 上学时他拿笔都有困难 - 痒吗?
Do anything different lately?
最近有什么不寻常的事?
You get a new baseball glove, a new kitten?
有了新棒球手套 小猫崽?
Well, the neighbors put in a pool, so he's been spending a lot of time over there.
社区里多了个泳池 他经常跑去那里玩
But, well, if it was something in the water, it would be everywhere, wouldn't it?
可如果水里有东西 那应该全身都有 对吧?
It is in the water. He's allergic to chlorine?
- 是在水里 - 他对氯过敏?
No...
不是...
He's allergic to summer lilac.
他对夏日紫丁香过敏
That's my lotion. And it's not in the pool.
那是我的乳液 泳池里没有
No, it's on the palms of his hands.
他手掌上有
In the pool is the neighbor's daughter.
泳池里要么是邻居的女儿
Or the neighbor's hot wife.
要么是邻居性感的妻子
Here's some lube.
给你润滑油
Sorry. Too late for your eyesight.
抱歉 视力没得治了
Endoscopy didn't reveal any lesions
内窥镜并未发现
in the small intestine.
小肠有损伤
I'm running PCR test now.
我正在做PCR检测
Found it in my office.
在我办公室发现的
Appears to be a gift. That can't be good.
似乎是个礼物 肯定不是好事
Damn it. You got her the job interview.
- 该死 - 你帮她争取到了工作面试
And that was supposed to be the end of it. I...don't take charity.
事情本该到此结束 我不接受施舍
Good for you! You loon.
行啊你! 笨蛋
I don't like owing people things.
我不喜欢欠别人
So either you're so insecure
你要么很没安全感
that you feel like you need to always have the upper hand, or you're so arrogant
觉得自己一定要占据上风 要么很傲慢
that the notion of a favor is insulting to you. Or it's your family,
"帮忙"这个想法对你而言都是种侮辱 要么就是你的家庭
some kind of immigrant pride thing.
移民者的自尊心
I'm betting on the last one.
我赌是最后一个
I just don't like it.
我只是不喜欢这样
It makes me feel...Icky.
会让我觉得... 不舒服
That's the reason? Ickiness?
就这原因? 不舒服?
You never even tried to analyze this?
你就没试着分析分析?
It's even crazier than the gift thing.
这比送礼还扯
House...
House...
there's no sign of tropheryma DNA.
没有发现tropheryma的DNA (惠普尔病的致病菌)
It's not Whipple's.
不是惠普尔病
Well...we did what we could.
我们尽力了
You sure you wanna do this?
你确定要这么做?
Relax.
别紧张
This is gonna make me very happy.
这样做会带给我快乐
Dr. Simpson. Heart rate's 140, pressure's dropping.
Simpson医生 心率140 血压下降
Get him adenosine, stat.
马上给他用腺苷酸
Patient's unstable. Surgery's off.
病人情况不稳定 手术中止
Arrhythmia's back. He's on Heparin and stable for now,
心律不齐又出现了 目前用了肝素 情况稳定
but this could put him at risk for stroke or embolism.
但这使他有可能中风或得血栓
Maybe he got bit by a spider.
也许他被蜘蛛咬了
The symptoms can take up to three days to manifest. He'd have localized pain.
- 症状也许要三天后才表现出来 - 他感到局部疼痛
LCDD?
轻链沉积病?
Almost always hits the kidneys.
总是碰上肾
Ah, Dr. Foreman. Perhaps you can help us.
啊 Foreman医生 也许你能帮我们
I can't decide whether to take out an "I told you so" ad
我下不了决定 是在新英格兰医学杂志上
in the New England Journal or stay classy
刊登广告 上书"我早告诉你了" 还是有点品位
and just spray-paint it on your car. You're off the case.
- 在你车上喷漆 - 这个病人不归你了
That seems like an overreaction.
你反应过度了吧
You dosed him. Couldn't stand to lose him as a patient,
你给他下药了 不想失去他这个病人
so you faked his symptom to prove you right. That's idiotic.
- 所以你伪造症状证明自己是正确的 - 太白痴了
Sorry. Don't apologize.
- 抱歉 - 别道歉
I don't know if you're power crazed or paranoid,
我不知道你是被权势冲昏了头脑还是疑神疑鬼
but I know she's right.
但她说得对
Two lives are in the balance here.
两条生命情况危急
House, I worked for you for seven years. I know how you operate.
House 我为你工作了七年 我知道你的手段
So when I see symptoms magically show up right when you need them--
所以你需要症状 症状就出现 我
And I was your boss for seven years.
我当了你上司七年
And I know what a suspicious, micromanaging hard-ass you are.
我知道你是多么多疑 顽固 小题大做
Why would I do this now?
我何苦要这么做啊
Knowing you can send me right back to jail?
明知道你可以直接送我回去蹲大牢
What'd you give him? Nothing!
- 你给他用了什么药? - 什么都没用!
You can't prove otherwise.
反正你也无法证明
So why don't you do the smart thing here?
不如做个聪明的决定吧?
You're off the case.
你不再负责这个病人
You no longer have access to this patient.
你不许再接触病人
You can't let him do this. He's the boss.
- 你不能让他这么做 - 他是头儿
And he's right.
而且他是对的
I assume you dosed the patient because you're really certain
你给病人下药 因为你很肯定
he has a neurological condition?
他神经有问题?
I assume you're interpreting my actions in the best possible light
你用这么乐观的方式解读我的行为
'cause you didn't get the job?
因为你没得到那份工作?
What's with you and Park?
你和Park怎么了?
Nothing.
没什么
I expect my people to lie better than that.
我希望我的手下撒谎有水平
Either you're getting her gifts because
要么你送她礼物是因为
you want her to like you, in which case I don't like you,
你希望她喜欢你 这样的话我可就不喜欢你了
or you're getting her gifts to screw with her.
要么你就是在耍她玩
In which case, I will be teaching you my secret homey handshake.
这样的话 我教你我的私房握手礼
I just...I thought it was interesting
我只是觉得很有意思
she couldn't accept that coffee.
她连杯咖啡都不接受
I wanted to see how deep it went.
我想知道究竟底限在哪里
But now? Oh, now I just want to win.
- 现在呢? - 现在我只想赢
What was in the box? Gift certificate.
- 盒子里是什么 - 代金卡
The spa.
SPA
Nah, that's not gonna do it.
啊 这可赢不了
You're up against a lifetime of training.
你的对手可是接受了一辈子这样的训练
If you wanna win, you gotta do something she can't possibly reciprocate.
你想赢 就得做些她无法回报的事
You gotta push her neuroses to the point where even she thinks that she's crazy.
你要把她逼到极端 让她觉得自己要疯了
One more favor.
再帮个忙
Then I promise, I'll leave you alone forever.
我保证 这以后我就不烦你了
Or I'm lying.
不然就是我撒谎
Either way, it's more interesting than whatever you're doing now.
不管怎样 肯定比你现在做的事有趣
Can I help you? I'm his wife.
- 需要帮忙吗 - 我是他妻子
We're separated. I heard he was sick.
我们分居了 听说他病了
I just... Wanted to see him.
我只是想来看看他
He's giving a kidney to someone he's never met?
他要把肾捐给未曾谋面的人?
He wants to, yeah.
他想这么做
I know he's talked about you. He's been alone all this time.
我知道他说起过你 他一直一个人
I'm sure it would mean a lot to him to see you.
能见你一面 他一定会很开心
I wanted to spend my life with him, but...
我很想和他共度余生 可是...
I need to feel like he loves me more than other people.
我希望能感觉到他爱我比爱别人多
Like he loves our kids more.
像是他更爱我们的孩子
Maybe that's selfish.
也许我太自私了
I should go.
我该走了
Was that my wife?
那是我妻子?
I don't know.
我不知道
You the guy, the kidney donor?
你就是那个捐肾的人?
There was a problem, but...
出现了一点小问题 不过...
I'm gonna try again.
我会再试试
Um...to give it to the same lady?
呃 还给那位女士?
She needs it.
她很需要
Okay. Never mind.
好吧 算了
Wait.
等等
What do you-- what do you want?
你想 你想怎么样?
Uh, it's nothing. It's just...
没什么 只是...
I have polycystic kidney disease.
我得了多囊肾病变
And I need a transplant, and they say I don't have much time,
我需要做移植手术 医生说我时日无多了
so when I heard that you were willing, I just...
我听说你愿意捐献 所以...
But I'm glad it's going to someone.
不过我很高兴能有人收益
I'll give it to you.
我给你吧
But you already promised it to someone else. I have another one.
- 你答应了要给别人的 - 我还有一个
Saving one life is good. Saving two is better.
救一个人很好 救两个人更好
You give away two kidneys, and you die.
拿走两个肾 你就死了
I could live on dialyses for years.
我可以做透析 活上几年
Yes, and-- and then you die. And then I could donate my other organs.
- 是啊 然后你还是死 - 然后我可以捐其他的器官
Heart, lungs.
心脏 肺
I could save four or five more lives.
再救四五个人
Foreman's gonna need a diagnostician.
Foreman需要找个诊断专家来
This guy is crazy.
这人完全疯了
Arrhythmia, muscle tremors, and, yes, mental changes.
心律不齐 肌肉战栗 以及心理变化
If his heart doesn't rupture, he's liable to rip it out and give it away.
如果他的心脏不崩裂 他很可能会把它挖出来送人
You know, the "down" vibe in here
这种沉闷的感觉
is totally ruining my Charlie's Angels fantasy.
完全毁了我对于"查理天使"的幻想
And that haircut isn't helping, either.
那发型也太倒胃口
It seems like Graves disease
似乎是格氏病
or some other thyroid issue. Is she on the team now?
- 或是其他甲状腺疾病 - 她这是归队了?
Like, forever?
不走了?
His thyroid levels were within normal range when he was admitted.
入院时他的甲状腺水平处于正常范围
Could be Coxsackie B virus. Or pericarditis.
- 柯萨奇病毒B - 或者心包炎
What about porphyria? It's a little weird without the rash,
那卟啉症呢? 不起疹子是挺怪
but it fits all of his other symptoms.
但其他症状都符合
And if it is acute intermittent porphyria,
如果是急性间歇卟啉症
that would explain why his symptoms keep recurring.
这就能解释为何他一再复发
It's unlikely... but it's possible. What else?
不太像 不过有可能 还有吗?
I said what else?
我说还有吗?
Oh, for...
哦 天...
There. That's better. Now, what else?
这样好多了 还有要说的吗?
Well, if there's nothing better than possible,
如果除了"可能"外没啥更好的建议
then possible gets upgraded to probable.
那么"可能"上升为"很有可能"
I'll start him on hematin. No, I'll go.
- 我这就给他测血色素 - 不用 我去吧
So what's the answer? Are you now on the team?
你的回答是什么? 你归队了?
Like, forever?
不离开了?
I don't know.
我不知道
'Cause I was thinking of ordering T-shirts.
我在考虑订统一T恤
I don't know...House. I mean, what am I supposed to do?
我不知道 ...House 我该怎么做?
I trained to be a Doctor.
我接受训练成为医生
I know how to take someone's pain away,
我知道怎么消除病人的疼痛
how to make a stopped heart beat again.
如果让停止的心跳复苏
We've brought people's kids back.
救回别人的孩子
Their husbands...
别人的丈夫...
So...guilt?
是内疚?
Yes, you were right. You're always right.
是的 你是对的 你总是对的
I just...
我只是...
I have the skills to help people.
我有能力救助别人
Is it okay for me to walk away from that
只因为我想享受快乐
because I...want to just have fun?
就把这些都丢弃 这样做可以吗?
Obviously not.
当然不
How's your patient?
你的病人如何了?
She died a few hours ago.
几小时前去世了
Thirteen is back.
13回来了
No department. No money.
没有公寓 没有钱
And somehow, you managed to con her into hanging around.
而你居然把她骗到这儿来
I have a gift.
我的天赋
What? It was a con.
- 怎么了? - 骗局
The patient was faking?
病人造假?
No, I was.
不 是我
I brought him in here under false pretenses.
我作假让他入院
Just to get his money.
就是为了赚他的钱
I ordered a bunch of random tests to keep him here.
我制定了一系列的随意测试 就为了让他留下
One of them was a head CT, which uses...
其中包括头部CT 用到了...
Iodine contrast. You think he's allergic to Iodine?
- 碘对比剂 - 你觉得他对碘过敏?
No, again. Just don't interrupt me.
再一次 不是 别打岔
Thirteen was right.
13是对的
This is a thyroid issue.
是甲状腺疾病
He has Plummer's disease.
他患有普鲁麦氏病
He has a nodule in his thyroid.
甲状腺里有结节
It produces excess hormone.
产生了过量的激素
Not enough to test abnormal,
量不会过大 所以变态反应测不出
just more than his brain is used to.
但是比大脑所习惯的要多
Just enough to make him irrationally generous, make him vulnerable to overheating.
足以让他变态般的慷慨 易受高温伤害
Then you pumped his body full of Iodine and kicked him into thyrotoxicosis.
接着你往他身体里注射了碘 使他甲状腺功能亢进
I said don't interrupt. But, yes, you're right.
我说了别打岔 不过是的 你说对了
Take out the nodule, he'll be fine.
取出结节 他就好了
Two days, one surgery.
两天 一个小手术
I now accept, that your all better.
我现在认可 你好多了
Where's my money? You made me sick.
- 我的钱呢? - 你让我生病了
You were already sick.
你早就病了
I just made you much, much worse.
我只是让你病重了些
Seriously...the money.
说真的... 钱呢
You're not giving it to me, are you?
你不给我了 是吗?
When you're facing death...
当你面对死亡时...
some things come into focus.
有些事会变得清晰
My wife. You love your family. You want them back.
- 我妻子 - 你爱你的家庭 你想回到他们身边
Your altruism was always a symptom.
你的无私一直是症状
No, it wasn't. I'm still gonna--
不 才不是 我还是要
Keep less? How much less?
留下更少? 多少是少?
Just enough to spoil your kids? No.
- 刚够宠溺你的孩子? - 不
But they need it more than people with TB
可他们比患有肾结核
or children in Indonesia with no eyes?
或是印尼瞎眼的孩子
Diagnosticians with hearts of gold?
和有着金子般的心灵的诊断医生更需要?
I don't wanna give you money because you're an ass.
我不给你钱 因为你是个混球
I was an ass last week.
上礼拜我是个混球
I love my family.
我爱我的家人
I want to be with them.
我想和他们在一起
That doesn't make me a bad person.
这并不代表我就是个坏人
No.
不
It makes you a healthy person.
这代表你是个健康的人
My mechanic called. He said the work's been paid for.
技工打来电话说 钱已经被付清了
You mentioned your car was in the shop.
你说你的车在店里
That's $4,500.
那可是4500块
Smile and say thank you.
笑一个 说句谢谢
Or I get you G.P.S.
不然我给你弄个GPS
You win.
你赢了
Thank you.
谢谢
Your car is getting fixed.
你的车在修了
You're right. She went for it.
你说对了 她真的信了
Good work.
干得好
Need a lift tomorrow?
明天送你一程?
'Cause your car is still in the shop.
你的车还在店里不是吗
I don't take charity. I'm just glad it's over.
我不接受施舍 我只是很高兴事情结束了
Nothing is ever over.
没有结束这回事
* To live, oh *
* To live, oh *
* and I've been trying hard against *
* and I've been trying hard against *
* unbelievable odds *
* unbelievable odds *
* gets so hard in times like now *
* gets so hard in times like now *
* to hold on *
* to hold on *
* but guns they wait to be stuck by *
* but guns they wait to be stuck by *
Wait a minute.
等一等
* there ain't no one goin' to turn me 'round *
* there ain't no one goin' to turn me 'round *
You're fired.
你被解雇了
Now what? House, I'm starving.
这是干嘛? House 我饿死了
I'm not joking. You're fired. Don't come in tomorrow.
我没开玩笑 你被炒鱿鱼了 明天别来了
House...
House...
I can work with people who've got nowhere else to go.
我可以和无处可去的人一起工作
People who got something to prove. People who just get off on weird cases.
或是想证明自己的人 或是刚结束古怪病案的人
What I can't work with is someone who's here
可如果对方来这里是想让自己心里好受
so she doesn't have to feel bad.
我无法和这样的人共事
* Places where they send you *
* Places where they send you *
You're trying to save me.
你想拯救我
Yes...I think that little of you and that much of me.
是啊... 我把你想得太渺小 把自己想得太伟大
* They'll zip you up and dress you down *
* They'll zip you up and dress you down *
* and stand you in a row *
* and stand you in a row *
* but you know you don't have to *
* but you know you don't have to *
* you can just say no *
* you can just say no *
Okay.
好吧
* and there ain't no one *
* and there ain't no one *
Bye, House.
再见 House
* Goin' to turn me around *
* Goin' to turn me around *
* there ain't no one *
* there ain't no one *
* goin' to turn me around *
* goin' to turn me around *
* ain't no one... *
* ain't no one... *
破烂熊字幕组 -==http://www.ragbear.com==- 欢迎加入
破烂熊字幕组 -==http://www.ragbear.com==- 欢迎加入